in this video I want to tackle our
intuition of electricity and its
physical properties specifically today
we're going to be talking about current
so if I ask you right now what is
current what would you say
a lot of this is a current is the flow
of electrons and that matches really
closely with Imperium definition of
current which is is equal to Q over T or
current is equal to the flow of charge
over time and I demonstrate in this
little circuit we have a battery which
supplies a voltage and one single wire
which closes the loop now a lot of us
I've seen animations like this that even
been described as electrons pushing each
other from one end to the other but that
raises the question we've all asked what
if we have a six million kilometer long
wire and we ran a current through that
what the electrons would push each other
all the way to the other side
for eternity well maybe not all of us
have questioned that but that leaves us
wondering if electrons are too slow to
transfer the information in current
carrying wire what does the answer that
question is electric field but first
we're going to talk about drift velocity
now a lot of us have heard about your
philosophy class and what it is is the
speed at which a charge carrier moves
from one end of the circuit to the other
in this circuit it could take up to an
hour for an electron to transfer from
the negative terminal to the positive
terminal now something doesn't add up
here because our internet speeds are
much faster than that and it's more like
in the nanoseconds the transfer
something from here to here so how does
information energy travel from one end
of the current carrying wire to another
I've been analogy for this is the water
hose and this water hose assuming is
filled with water can be treated like a
current carrying wire with the water
decided being like the electrons in the
wire so if you were to put this on
faucet and crank up the pressure the
pressure waves would propagate through
the hose to the other end before the
wonderful fits dude the water molecule
here doesn't have to travel all the way
around to come out the other side the
pressure which travels at the speed of
sound propagates the information to the
other side of the hose for this water
molecule to come out and that's exactly
how a wire works and in a
current-carrying wire instead of
pressure
we have electric fields and those
propagate at the speed of light or
almost the speed of light and that
carries the information for the
electrons further down the wire to move
another question might have asked is
about capacitors now we know a parallel
plate capacitor there are no conductors
in between to carry charges therefore
according to the appearing definition of
current there is no current however
there is something called displacement
currents and that has to do with the
electric field so it's really
interesting to see how electric fields
and charge is very important for example
in chemistry we want to count for every
single charges flowing through the
circuit let's say in a battery
whereas in signal processing we want to
make sure that Layton sees as well as
possible and therefore we calculate the
permeability of the electric field I
want to end the video by reminding you
to never stop question deeper and for
those of you who already thought a step
ahead and asking how electric fields
properly information to space well honey
physicists have an explanation for you